NATHANIEL POPPER,AUTHOR OF DIGITAL GOLD,REPORTER,NEW YORK TIMES,SAN FRANSISCO Bitcoin is supposed to run on a sort of Democratic process.
ナザニエル ポッパー、デジタル金貨の著者、ニューヨークタイムズ レポーター、サンフランシスコ ビットコインは、民主的なプロセスで実行されるようになっています。
aimed  at  reaching a consensus.
合意に達することを目的として。
But over the last year or so , It's been increasingly hard to find any consensus about what this thing should look like.
しかし、去年1年くらいからBitcoinがどのようなものであるかということに対する 合意が だんだんと見つけられなくなっています。
At the most basic level a battle over a Bitcoin today is about how many transactions should be running through the network.
最も基本的なレベルで 今日の ビットコイン上で繰り広げられる闘いというのは、 ビットコインネットワーク上でいくつの取引が処理してよいか、ということに対するものです。
On one side , you have this camp that wants to expand the number of transactions that can go through the network
一方の側では、ネットワークを介して行うことができる トランザクションの数を拡大したいと考えています。
So that anyone can send the transaction over the network anytime essentially for free
そうすれば、誰でも無料でいつでも基本的にネットワーク上 でトランザクションを送信できるようにすることができます。
On the other side, you have this camp that essentially wants to keep Bitcoin smaller
もう一方の側では、基本的に、ビットコインを小さな ネットワークのままキープしたいそうすれば
in order to assure its security and de-centralization of  the network.
そのセキュリティおよびネットワークの 脱中央集権化を確保できるからです。
This battle has  become a sort of  political civil war within the Bitcoin community
この戦いはビットコインのコミュニティ 内での政治内戦のようなものとなっています
where the two sides are really fighting over the fate what this system looks like.
双方はこのビットコインシステムがど のようなるべきかという運命を決める戦いをしています。
TRUST DISRUPTED BITCOIN AND THE BLOCKCHAIN TechCrunch Originals
信用の創造的破壊 ビットコインとブロックチェイン TechCrunch Originals
III. Bitcoin in Search of Itself
3．ビットコインの自分探し
1 Megabyte: Cap on the amount of data processed by the Bitcoin network every 10 minutes
1メガバイト：ビットコインネットワークによって処理される10分ごとのデータの量の意図的制限
1 Megabyte : Cap on the amount of data processed by the Bitcoin network every 10 minutes 7 : Maximum number of transactions the Bitcoin network can handle every second
7：ビットコインネットワークが１秒で処理できるトランザクションの数
We are moving to a potentially dangerous point of information
私たちは、情報の潜在的に危険なポイントに来ています
Today's society has less a kind of  freedoms of expression and freedoms of  association
今日の社会は、以前と比べて 表現の自由がより少なく、 つながりの自由がより少なくなりました。
than previous generations because the technology didn't exist and wasn't sort of archiving and collecting at all and the conversations are happening in physical environment where everything is recorded.
前の世代では、技術が存在しなかっため、会話が保存されたり 集められたりされることはありませんでした。いまでは、 すべてのことが記録されるような環境で人々は会話をしているのです。
As things move onto the Internet, *as default* everything is being recorded
インターネット上に さまざまなことが移動すると、 基本的に、すべてが記録されてしまいます。
and you also see this with sort of reactions to Snowden's revelations that
あなたはまた、スノーデンがやった NSAによる個人情報収集という事実の暴露についての 人々の 反応からそれが見えます。
things are actually more invasive than people anticipated
それは、実際に人々の予想以上に侵略的であり
and National government are sort of  probing everything up about all basically everybody
国や政府はすべてを スキャンすなわち皆さんを スキャンしてるという事実です。
ADAM BACK,PRESIDENT,BLOCKSTREAM,BLOCKCHAIN SOFTWARE COMPANY,SAN FRANSISCO You don’t have to have committed a crime or be suspicious to commit a crime
アダム バック、ブロックストリーム社 社長、ブロックチェーンソフトウエアの会社、サンフランシスコ 彼らは、あなたが犯歴があるとか犯罪を犯すと怪しんでいるとかは、関係なく  、
They just are recording all just in case they want to  look *further*
すべての情報を念のため記録しています。
What encryption technology  does is  hold the balance back of it so that people are regaining  that privacy expectations they have
暗号化技術があることで、我々はそのバランスを取り戻します。 人々は、再び自分のプライバシーを守りたいという期待にこたえることができる。
As we work on  improving Bitcoin and scaling Bitcoin you have to preserve the  security properties.
我々はビットコインを改善し、ビットコインをスケールを広げながらも 自分のセキュリティを保持する必要があります。
Bitcoin security and permissionlessness depends on de-centralization.
ビットコインのセキュリティと承認不要な性質は、非中央集権に依存していいます。
BOBBY LEE,CEO, BTCC, BITCOIN EXCHANGE AND MINING COMPANY,SHANGHAI So, Today we have this 1 Megabyte blocks which effectively goes about 5 to 7 transactions per second.
ボビーリー、最高経営責任者、BTCC、ビットコイン取引所および鉱山会社 我々は、いま、1メガバイト制限がありそのせいで1秒間の取引は5から7までしかできません。
And for the first 7 years, its never been a problem. Now we are in the 8th year,
最初の7年間は、それは問題ではありませんでした。 そして我々は8年目に突入しました。
blocks are getting *full*  its kind of the highway, 8 lanes highways are finally getting congested.
ブロックは だんだん満タンのなっており、まるで 8レーンの高速道路が 、ついに、大渋滞になったのです。
So, now the questions is  ,do we impose or   just build 69 lane highway or  32 lane highway that's kind of ridiculous.
だから、今の問題は、我慢するか、単に69車線の高速とか 32車線の高速道路を構築するかです。 これは馬鹿げています。
The simplest engineering solution is to make the block size bigger.
最も簡単な技術ソリューションは、ブロックサイズを大きくすることです。
We impose in higher throughput  more cars, more buses , more carpooling. That kind of stuff.
より高いスループットができるようにする、 多くの車、より多くのバス、より多くの相乗りができる。そのようなものです。
It kind of combination of both The way I see it is Not just transporting a  Bitcoin layer.
それは両方の組み合わせですね。 私の理解では、 ビットコイン層のデータ転送だけでなく、
But the additional layer on top of Bitcion layers, we call it  Layer 2 services.
ビットコイン層の上に追加の層、我々はそれを レイヤ２サービスといいますが、それを置きます。
where there are sidechains, other technology like a  lightening
そこでは、サイドチェインやライトニングといわれる技術が使われています。
Those will solve some of the  capacity and transaction problems
それらは、いくつかの容量の問題とトランザクションの問題を解決します。
Layer 2 protocols are more network efficient.
レイヤ2プロトコルは、ネットワーク効率がよいものです。
They don’t broadcast transactions. They send transactions between the people involved in payment and maybe routers.
彼らは、トランザクションを全体にブロードキャストしません。 彼らは、支払に関わる人々とそれを仲介する人々のみにトランザクションを送信します。
And they also improve the speed of transaction So transaction can clear *quite* instantly.
それにより、取引の時間が改善され、 結果 取引の決済をかなり早く終わらせることができます。
whereas Bitcoin transactions have some kind of tradeoff
一方、ビットコインの取引は　ある　トレードオフ が存在します。
where you might get 10 min or  20min settlement time depending on the amount **
取引の金額によりますが、決済の時間が10分から20分かかります。
a part of the engineering community thinks that better solution is that
エンジニアリングコミュニティの一部の人々が考える、 よりよい解決策は
go with what called Off-blockchain solutions
ブロックチェーンの外のソリューションを使うことです。
where transactions don’t settle on the Bitcoin blockchain but happen off of  the Bitcoin blockchain
取引は、ビットコインのブロックチェインの上で決済せず、 その外で決済されるのです。
This's  been a lot of work on that, a lot of  innovation on that I am actually pretty excited about all of that  work
それを実現するために、かなりの努力やイノベーションがなされてきました。 わたしはその作業にとても興奮しています。
It's really interesting technical work.
それは、とても面白い技術的な作業です。
My big disagreement has been that we should not put all of our eggs in one basket
私の大きな意見の相違は、 我々は一つのかごに私たちのすべての卵を入れてはならないことです。
we should also do the dumb engineering thing in just increasing the block size now
我々はまた、今のブロックサイズを大きくするために、 めんどうな開発作業を行う必要があります
because there is no reason not to.
やらない理由がないからです。
The scaling advantages from layer 2 are much larger and increasing the block size.
レイヤ2を使うことによる、スケーリングの利点は非常に大きく、 ブロックサイズを大きくしています。
Specificity I want to say that assuming the layer 2 technology * pans out* most people expect.
特に私は言いたいのは、 レイヤ2テクノロジーは、 人々が期待するように うまくいったということです。
It is probable that story next year  would be the different one which is the enormous *size of*  capacity.
私は、かなりの確率で、来年話してることは、いまと全然違うと思います。
You are saying that the debate we are having now about scaling vs decentralizing
あなたがおっしゃっているのは 今我々が行っている分散化 VS  スケーリン- グ議論は、
might not be a debate  a year from now.
今から1年もたてば、なくなっていることだということでしょうか？
yeah , I think that  is *my* expectation.
ええ、私は そうなると思います。
All the transactions in a block can carry a  transaction fee that's paid to the miners as a* bribe* essentially to include my transaction in your block instead of  somebody else's
ブロック内すべてのトランザクションは、代わりの他の誰かのより、 私のトランザクションが、あなたのブロックに含まれるため、 まるで賄賂として マイナー達に に支払われる取引手数料を運ぶことができます。
If I  have my way , we  will lhave much bigger blocks.
もし私のやり方でやるなら、かなり大きなブロックを持つことになります。
Transaction fee is always really low.
取引手数料は、常に本当に低くなり、
if you do a math of millions of transactions in a block
あなたは、１つのブロック内の数百万のトランザクションの計算処理を行う場合
each paying  is a cent or half of cent for a transaction fee
1取引の各手数料の支払いは、１セントとか0.5セント
that will more that make up for declining the block award
ブロックからの報酬の減少を補う金額以上になります
The opponents who want scaling fast are saying  we should make the block bigger and put in lot of transactions.
早くスケーリングして規模を大きくしたい相手は、我々は、もっとブロックを大きく そして、取引の多く入れなければならないと言っています。
Downside is if you make the blocks really big,
欠点は、もしブロックのサイズをかなり大きくしたら、
then it affects how well other people can own and distribute this global ledger
普通の人たちが いったい、うまくこのグローバル勘定元帳データを 自分のコンピュータに保持しそして、分散してもてるのか。
so only  a few people can keep up with so-called big blocks the world falls in more centralized way of managing Bitcoin.
もし、ごく少数の人だけが　いわゆる 大きなブロックを管理するとしたら 昔ながらの中央集権的なやり方でビットコインを管理することになります。
Ideological concern is that we will end up in a place where Bitcoin is only a tool for elites and  Big companies I think that those are really overblown.
イデオロギー的な懸念は、 ビットコインがエリートや大企業のためのただのツールで終わってしまう、というものです。 私はそれは、とても誇張された話だと思います。
Initially I think there was an idea that Bitcoin could be a lot of different things
当初、ビットコインはたくさんの、 今までと違ったものになるｌかもしれないという考えがあったと思います
that could be a digital gold
それはデジタル金貨かもしれません
also could be a new kind of Paypal
また、ペイパルみたいなものかもしれません
where you can run transactions around the world
あなたは、世界中の取引を実行することができます
As time is  going on , I think that it become  clear that if the system is going to expand It cannot be everything to everyone
時間が進むごとに、システムが拡大していますが、 これがあらゆる人の全員のためのシステムでありつづけることは、無理だということが 明らかになってくるでしょう。
It has to choose what it wants to be
どうなるべきかをある時点で選択する必要があります
based on Nathaniela Popper's Digital Gold
ナザニエル ポッパーのデジタルゴールドに基づいて